(Syncro: F.B Cavalcante)
Just keep the door covered.
把门保持关闭
Janice, have you got a screwdriver?
Janice, 你有螺丝刀吗?
Hello, Doctor Arnold?
你好, Arnold 博士?
No, Winslet, it's Janice.
不, Winslet, 是Janice
Doctor Sal's a little tied up at the moment.
Sal 医生目前有点忙
- Tell him not now, Winslet.
- Not now, Winslet.
- 跟他说现在不行, Winslet  - 现在不行, Winslet
Wait a minute.
等一下
Doctor Arnold specifically asked me
to find any other containers...
Arnold博士特意让我找找有没有一样的箱子
with the same serial number as the one
that contained that sphere thing.
要序列号跟以前那个一样, 里面有那种球体的箱子
Said it was very important.
她说这事很重要
Now I've been doing that
over and above everything else
我一直把这事放在其它事情前面
that I'm supposed to be doing down here.
本来我的其它事情也不少
I've given it my full attention.
我全部注意力都放在这上面了
Taken me the best part of two weeks.
把我这两周最好的时间段都占据了
And, as a matter of fact, I have found
a large number of crates with the same code.
事实上, 我发现了大量同样编码代码的板条箱
- Triple A stroke RH stroke 2961.
- Thank you, Winslet. No time.
- AAA/RH/2961  - 谢谢你, Winslet, 没时间
Some of them have the letters...
其中一些上面还有字母
A, U, T, O, N.
A, U, T, O, N.​
Winslet, not now.
Winslet, 现在不行
I have a satellite downlink,
an expensive satellite downlink,
我这里有个卫星下行连接, 非常昂贵的卫星下行连接
due any...
随时都...
（下行连接  已生效）
- Oh God, I'm tired.  - We could always
use some of next week's satellite window.
- 天啊, 好累   - 我们可以等下周的卫星档期
You must be joking.
开什么玩笑
I'm going to beat this thing if kills me.
如果它杀了我, 我会砸了这玩意儿(?)
- I can't believe you used Meccano.
- Nothing wrong with that.
- 不能相信你居然用了麦卡诺  - 没什么问题啊
(麦卡诺: 商标名, 主要是钢铁组合的模型玩具)
Ah, here we go.
啊, 好戏来了
- Anything?
- Still just background radiation.
- 有动静吗?  - 还是只有背景辐射
Let's see if I can filter out some
to the extraneous stuff.
我们来看看能不能过滤掉一些无关的
Ah, nobody loves you.
啊, 没人爱你
Janice, get your notepad.
Janice, 去拿你的笔记本
Note the time.
记录一下时间
My God, what have I done?
上帝啊, 我做了什么?
(苏醒 10:05 AM)
(发光 规律性脉动 10:07...)
Perhaps we should shut it off now.
也许我们应该现在就关掉它
It's picked up on something.
Or something's picked up on it.
它收到了什么信号, 或者是什么东西收到了它的
It's having...a conversation.
它在进行...对话
It's transmitting.
在传输什么
Terminating the satellite link.
正在断开卫星连接
That's it.
好了
Janice, keep away!
Janice, 躲开!
Auton 三部曲 第一集
(Sincro: F.B Cavalcante)
(翻译: 巴蛮子sz)
Doctor Arnold.
Arnold 博士
- Code Seven now on site.
- Protocol one nine zero.
- 出现7号情况  - 按规程190处理
All non-essential personnel are evacuated
所有无关紧要的人员已经撤离
to safe house with full decontamination.
并进入安全屋进行了全面消毒
Listen, do you have any idea what...
听着, 你是否知道·...
Heard those nasty rumours
about containment teams?
听说过关于遏制组的吓人传言不?
You don't think.
都不敢想
They'll be here any minute now.
他们现在随时都会到达这里
- Winslet?  - What?
- Winslet?   - 什么?
- I'm sorry I said you had bad breath.
- When?
- 很抱歉我说你有口臭  - 什么时候?
When did you have bad breath,
or when did I say it?
什么时候你有口臭, 还是什么时候我说了这个?
- Doesn't matter.  - Don't move!
- 没关系了  - 不许动！
The laboratory's been secured, sir.
If you'd like to come this way.
这件实验室已经被保护起来了, 头儿, 你们跟我走这边吧
This is where it was.
这是它之前的位置
Dead? Dead.
死了吗? 死了
Make a preliminary examination.
做一个初步检查
The usual tests. Open your box of tricks.
常规检测, 打开你的宝贝箱子
Did you know her?
你认识她吗?
Do you think we could put our hands down now?
你觉得我们可以把手放下来了不?
Doctor Sally Arnold,
Facility director and head of research?
Sally Arnold 博士, 基地主管兼研究负责人是吗?
Pleased to meet you. May I ask...
很高兴见到你. 我能不能问一下...
- And who is that?
- Winslet. Graham Winslet, archivist.
- 那位是谁?   - Winslet, Graam Winslet, 保管员
Non-essential. What are you doing here,
Mister Winslet?
小角色. 你在这里做什么, Winslet 先生?
- You should have been evacuated.
- I'm afraid I wasn't ready in time.
- 你应该疏散走了才对  - 当时我没及时准备好
- Oh. - Sorry.
- 哦  - 抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉?
All right, lads.
好了, 小伙子们
You'd better let them
have a general sniff around, Ramsay.
你最好让他们四处探查一下, Ramsay
- Is there a guard on the main entrance?
- Already taken care of.
- 主入口有人守卫吗?   - 已经有人盯着
Diligent as always, Ramsay.
一如既往地勤奋啊, Ramsay
I hope you didn't burn your clothes.
我期望你们没有烧掉你们的衣服
It would be such a waste.
那样很浪费的
Is this yours, Doctor.
这是你的吗, 博士?
Yes. Useful when I'm working late.
是的, 我加夜班的时候用得着
Which is most nights.
大部分晚上她都加夜班
Particle traces on here?
这里有粒子痕迹吗?
What about the woman?
这个女人呢?
Massive localised energy release.
有大规模的局部能量释放
Knocked out her entire nervous system.
击倒了她整个神经系统
- Did the thing just explode?
- No. If it just exploded,
- 那个东西只是爆掉了而已?  - 不, 如果只是爆掉...
- there'd be more debris left.
- What are you saying?
- 应该有更多碎片留下来  - 你在说什么?
That it did something a bit
cleverer than just exploding.
那它不仅仅是爆掉, 而是很聪明地干了点什么
My name is Lockwood.
我的名字是 Lockwood
I am the head of this containment team.
我是遏制小组的头儿
This is a code seven situation,
现在出现的是7号情况
so your death certificates have
already been prepared by UNIT.
所以你的死亡证明已经被 UNIT 准备好了
With luck, we won't find it
necessary to issue them.
幸运的话, 我们可能发现没必要发出来
This is Doctor Daniel Matthews, my assistant.
这位是Daniel Matthews 博士, 我的助手
Let me remind you that under the terms
of your contract with UNIT,
让我提醒你们一下, 根据你们跟 UNIT 签订的协议
you're obliged to give me the fullest
cooperation during this investigation.
在这次调查期间, 你们必须给与我全面合作
Mister Winslet, perhaps you'd like
to go and put your clothes back on...
Winslet 先生, 也许你可以去把你自己的衣服穿上...
...and wait in your office.
...在你的办公室等着
Right.
好
Did you think my men were going to shoot you?
你们是不是认为我的人刚才要射杀你们?
At one point, yes, it did cross my mind.
有那么一会儿, 是的, 这个念头真的从我脑子里闪现过
You thought you'd glimpsed the forbidden fruit,
你觉得你瞥见了禁果
that we were here to stop the truth getting out.
或者觉得我们是来防止真相泄漏出去
Something like that.
差不多吧
Perhaps we are here to stop something getting out.
也许我们来这里是为了阻止某种东西跑出去的
Was she a friend?
她是你的朋友?
I knew her too. It was years ago.
我也认识她, 好多年前了
She's in shock.
她吓坏了
She's no use to me at the moment.
这会儿她对我没用了
Take care of her, Doctor Matthews.
照看一下她, Matthews 博士
I feel stupid.
我觉得好蠢
It's just shock.
只是吓着了
Yes.
是的
Carry on.
继续吧
You've worked here for six years,
according to your records.
你在这里工作了六年, 根据你的档案
Very fastidious, not a great socialiser.
非常苛刻, 不善交际
Seven years.
七年
Seven. Yes.
七年, 是的
How come you didn't make it to the safe house?
怎么可能你没来得及去安全屋呢?
- I told you, I wasn't ready in...
- In time. Yes, I know.
- 我告诉过你, 我没有来..  - 没来得及, 是的, 我知道
- But why weren't you ready in time?
- I don't know.
- 但你为什么没有来得及?   - 我不知道
- Not like you.  - How would you know?
- 这不像你  - 你怎么知道?
Not like your personality profile.
跟你的个性档案描述不符
On the computer at UNIT HQ.
UNIT 总部的电脑上都有
Geneva.
日内瓦
Been there?
去过吗?
Geneva?
日内瓦?
No.
没有
I can't believe you used Meccano.
不敢相信你还用了麦卡诺
Perhaps we should shut it off now.
也许我们现在应该关掉它
- All right?  - Fine. Thanks.
- 没事吧?    - 还好, 谢谢
You should finish your tea.
你应该把茶喝完
It's hot and sweet. It's good for shock.
很热很甜, 适合稳定情绪
How did you know Janice?
你怎么认识 Janice 的?
Oh, at university.
噢, 在大学
Did you like her?
你喜欢她吗?
It was a long time ago.
那是好久以前了
Is your Mister Lockwood always so cold?
你们的Lockwood 先生总是这么冷冰冰的吗?
Lockwood?
Lockwood?​
He's a breed apart.
他另外一种人
But I've worked with him long enough
to know he's the best there is.
但我跟他共事很久了, 知道他是最强的
I see.
我明白了
Do you have any idea what's happened here?
你对这里发生了什么有了解吗?
- Yes, we have plenty of ideas.
- Like what?
- 是的, 我们了解很多情况  - 比如说?
Oh, no need to know, is it?
噢, 没必要知道, 是吧?
Why is Lockwood so convinced
there's no contamination risk?
为什么 Lockwood 如此确信没有污染风险?
I mean, that thing exploded.
I don't know what was inside it.
我是说, 那个东西爆炸了, 我不知道里面有什么
If you didn't know what was inside it,
why did you subject it to transmissions
如果你不知道里面有什么, 为什么要让它传输信息
from UNIT's most powerful
deep-space scanning satellites?
连的还都是 UNIT 最强大的深空扫描卫星
Because...
因为...
Because it was the only course
of relevant experimentation left.
因为这是唯一剩下的相关实验过程
I'd drawn a blank with the damn thing,
thought it was dead.
那个破玩意儿我一直什么结果也没得到, 以为它是个死的
I tried every test I could think of.
我试过了我能想到的每项测试
That is my job, Doctor Matthews.
Assess and catalogue.
这是我的工作, Matthews 博士, 评估、分类
I knew it was of extra-terrestrial origin.
我知道它是来自外星的
Wasn't just a meteor.
It appeared to be manufactured,
但又不是颗流星. 看起来是制造出来的
so I speculated...
于是我推断...
- Oh, you speculated.  - Yes.
- 噢, 你推断...  - 是的
We don't exactly have information
here at our fingertips, I'm afraid.
恐怕我们手头并没有信息
This place was a sort of forgotten
Aladdin's Cave until about five years ago.
这个地方被遗忘了, 跟阿拉丁的山洞似的, 直到五年前
It was a mess. Mountains of old paperwork.
一团乱麻, 数不清的文书工作
Winslet hasn't even got a
tenth of the way through it.
这一路上, Winslet 做的连一成都不到
We're working blind-folded most of.
我们一直都在蒙着眼瞎摸
Are you saying you know more about it?
你是说你知道它更多情况?
Where do you get your information?
你是从哪儿获取信息的?
I think you're ready to speak to Lockwood.
我觉得你已经准备好跟 Lookwood 谈话了
Are we in danger?
我们有危险吗?
It's possible.
有可能
So where were you when it all happened?
那事情发生的时候你们在哪儿?
Storage bay one, you said just now.
一号储物岛, 你刚才说的
- Yes.  - And you heard the alarm,
- 是的  - 然后你听到了警报
and you thought I think I'll just stay
here and pick my nose, is that it?
然后你想, 我还是待在这里挖我的鼻子, 是这样吗?
- No, no.  - Well then, what?
- 不, 不是  - 那, 是怎样的
Doctor Arnold was conducting
her experiment in her laboratory
Arnold 博士在她的实验室进行她的实验
on this alien artefact, serial code
triple A stroke RH stroke 2961,
实验对象是这个外星物品, 编号 AAA/RH/2961
and she asked me to find
any other containers with that code.
而且她让我找同样编号的其它箱子
Because she thought there might be more of them?
因为她觉得还有更多同样的?
Or anything that would help her identify
what she was dealing with.
或者任何其它东西, 只要能有助于她识别出她正在对付的是什么
She wasn't dealing with anything, Mister Winslet
她没在对付任何东西, Winslet 先生！
She was tampering with the unknown,
which is always pretty dangerous.
她在玩耍她不懂的东西, 这总是相当危险的
Did you find any other crates with
the same code on them, by the way?
对了, 你找到了其它有同样编号的板条箱了吗?
- No.  - Greyhound One to Greyhound Leader.
- 没有  - 灰狗一号呼叫灰狗队长
- Greyhound Leader.
- We have a problem.
- 我是灰狗队长  - 我们有问题了
- Same as the woman?
- I should say so.
- 跟那个女人一样的?   - 可以这么说
Mister Lockwood, what is going on?
Lockwood 先生, 什么情况
- Just Lockwood. No Mister.  - What is going on?
- 就叫 Lockwood, 不用叫先生  - 什么情况?
Exits are already secured.
出口已经把守住了
- What are we looking for?
- I don't know, exactly.
- 我们在找什么?   - 我不知道, 确切地说
Whatever it is, it can't be very big.
不管是什么, 应该不会很大
- Well, he didn't see it coming.
- Where is it going?
- 嗯, 他没看到它过来  - 那它又去哪儿了?
Well, presuming it started here
好, 假设它从这里开始
Oh, let's presume.
噢, 我们假设
- Too many variables give me a headache.
- It's going through the storage bays,
- 变数太多让我头疼  - 它穿过了这些储物岛
whatever it is you're talking about. Look.
不管你们在说的是什么. 你看
Well, what are you talking about?
好了, 你们在说的是什么?
Carry on, Ramsay, and see that
Doctor Arnold is kept out of harm's way.
继续吧 Ramsay, 同时确保Arnold 博士处于危险地带之外
What have we got?
我们有什么?
We haven't got any of the right
equipment, for a start.
比如说, 我们一件合适的装备都没有
This was a code seven, contamination risk.
这可是7号情况, 有污染风险
Yes. Bit of a balls-up, isn't it.
是啊, 事有点大, 对吧
I should have twigged there was no danger
of contamination the moment I saw the code.
在我看见代号那会儿, 我应该就直接说没有危险
- Triple A   - RH 2961.
- 3个A  - RH 2961
Seems no one here knew what it meant.
看来这里没人知道这是什么意思
But I didn't expect it to
turn into a bug hunt either.
但我估计它也不是抓抓虫子这种事
- This is something new.
- Should we call for back-up?
- 这是个新情况  - 我们应该呼叫支援吗?
To pick over our remains.
来抬我们的遗体吗
Great sense of humour, Lockwood.
幽默感不错, Lockwood
Great.
好
Sorry.
抱歉
- What did he say?  - Who?
- 他说什么?   - 谁?
- This Lockwood.  - Not much.
- 这个 Lockwood  - 没什么
What do you think of him?
I think he's a bit high-handed.
你觉得他怎么样? 我觉得他有点专横
Sorry about Janice.
Janice 的事很抱歉
We've got to find a way to track the damn thing.
我们得想个办法追踪这该死的东西
There's nothing feasible with the
level of equipment we've got here.
就我们手头这些设备的级别, 没有什么可行性
What is it they say about a bad workman?
对于一个拙劣的工人他们怎么说的?
(英语俗语 A bad workman quarrels with his tools
技术拙劣的工人抱怨自己的工具)
Oh, you're calling me a bad workman.
噢, 你把我称作拙劣的工人
What do you want to do, Dan?
你想怎么做, Dan?
Join the search. See what else has got
hidden away here, what it might be after.
加入搜索工作. 看看还有什么藏在这里, 它的企图又是什么
Our esteemed Doctor Sally Arnold apparently
instructed Mister Personality Winslet...
我们可敬的 Sally Arnold 博士显然已经让 Winslet 先生...
...to conduct a thorough search for
anything else with the same code.
...全面搜索了有同样编码的其它箱子
But would he draw back?
I still think it's worth double-checking.
但他会怠工吗? 我还是觉得值得核查一遍
I never trusted the brain cell count
in research establishments.
对研究机构的事我从不相信人脑细胞
All right, Have Ramsay bring
Sally Arnold to her laboratory.
好吧, 让 Ramsay 把 Sally Arnold 带到她的实验室
I shall be waiting to give her my charm offensive.
我将等着给她展开我的魅力攻势
Doctor Arnold? Come with me, please.
Arnold 博士吗? 请跟我来
- You just sit tight, Mister Winters.
- Winslet. Graham Winslet. Archivist.
- 你坐着就行, Winters 先生  - 是 Winslet. Graham Winslet. 保管员
Whatever.
随便吧
So he's finally deigned to speak with me, has he?
所以他终于屈尊要和我谈话了, 是吗?
- Who would that be, Doctor?
- Your boss, Lockwood.
- 你说谁, 博士?   - 你的老大, Lockwood
I believe he does want a word with you, yes, Doctor.
我相信他确实想和你聊一聊, 是的, 博士
I suppose all this is pretty routine
for you, Sergeant.
我想这一切对你来说都是很常规的, 中士
- That's right, Doctor.
- Where exactly are you taking me?
- 没错, 博士  - 你到底要带我去哪里?
- Your laboratory, Doctor.
- This is the long way.
- 你的实验室, 博士  - 这路好远
Come on, I'll show you a short cut.
来吧, 我给你展示一条捷径
Do sit down.
请坐下
What did you make of these symbols?
你用这些符号在做什么
What did I make of them?
I've never seen anything like them.
我用它们做什么? 我都从来没见过这样的
All right, all right.
好吧, 好吧
Did you think, oops, dear me, what have I done?
你有没有想过：糟糕, 我啊, 我做了什么啊?
Because I'd like to put to you that is
what you should have been thinking,
因为我要把你带入你应该要考虑的问题
given that something is now
crawling around the building
因为某个东西已经在这个建筑里四处爬了
apparently with the intention
of wiping out my team.
它显然有企图要消灭我的小组
- Something? What is this something?  - That.
- 某个东西? 某个东西是什么?   - 那个
You mean it didn't just vaporise when it exploded.
你是说它爆炸的时候不只是蒸发了
Doctor Sal is thinking.
Sal 博士开始用脑子了
Doctor Sal, that's what all
your chums call you, isn't it?
Sal 博士, 你那些密友都这么称呼你, 是吧?
The insightful UNIT research scientist?
富有洞察力的 UNIT 科学家?
Gifted, highly qualified?
有天赋, 高素质?
A working class comprehensive
school girl who ended up...
出身于工人阶级综合学校, 却最终...
with degrees in medicine,
physics, chemistry and biology.
获得了医学、物理、化学和生物学学位
I see you've read my file.
看来你读了我的档案
You're a bit of a maverick
in the scientific community.
你在科学界算是个独行侠
Not afraid to put forward new and untested ideas.
从不畏惧实施新颖而未经检验的想法
I suppose that accounts for
the stupidity of your actions here.
我觉得那就是你在这里做出愚蠢行为的原因
- It's easy to be wise with hindsight.
- Wisdom does not come into it.
- 事后扮明智总是很容易  - 这里没有明智什么事
Some excrement has hit the fan,
大粪扔到了风扇上
and you, Doctor Sal,
were the idiot who turned the fan on.
而你, Sal 博士, 就是那个打开风扇的白痴
I was doing my job.
我只是在做我的工作
It's a job which I happen to consider important.
只是这份工作我恰好觉得挺重要
I can't help it if UNIT doesn't fund us properly.
UNIT 不能给我们提供足够资金的话, 我就帮不上忙了
I work with the best information
that I have available to me.
我充分利用我所能得到的信息
In my opinion, underfunding of this
facility makes it a dangerous liability.
以我所见, 资金不足加大了这个设施的危险倾向
However, these are not matters
然而, 这些并不重要
for mere slaves of the UNIT bureaucracy like ourselves.
我们只是 UNIT 官僚体系的奴隶
I'm here to pick up the pieces.
我来拼一下情况
I'm your alien artefact
serial code triple A RH 2961.
我是你的外星物品, 编号 AAA/RH/2961
You connect me up to the widest range of
deep-space signals available to mankind
你把我连上了人类所能获得的范围最广的深空信号
Why?
为什么?
Because it hadn't responded
to any other kind of test.
因为它对其它种类的测试都没有响应
God save us from mavericks.
上帝把我们从独行侠手中救出来吧
You can test a gun all you like,
but it doesn't work until you pull the trigger.
一把枪你想怎么测试都行, 但在你扣动扳机之前, 它是不会工作的
You're saying I pulled the trigger?
你是说是我扣动了扳机?
It recognised one of the signals
from out there in deep space.
它识别出了一个来自深空的讯号
It came alive and received instructions.
它苏醒过来, 接收了指令
Now, what kind of an instruction
is please vaporise?
现在看看, “请你爆炸”是一个什么样的指令?
Not a very friendly one.
肯定是个不友好的指令
And this artefact was undoubtedly
talking to a friend,
但这个物件毫无疑问跟它一个朋友交流了
so perhaps it was instructed to do something else.
所以它有可能被指派去干点什么事情
So you're saying it atomised
in order to reform itself...
所以你是说它蒸发掉只是为了重组...
...into something that could move?
变成一个能移动的东西?
And kill. You saw nothing?
还能杀人. 你什么也没看见吗?
I saw a flash.
我看见一道闪光
I heard Janice and I blacked out.
我听到 Janice 叫喊, 然后我晕过去了
It's the mobility that's important.
重要的是它能移动了
It's going somewhere.
它要去别的地方
It wants something.
它想要某种东西
That'll be us in the shit, then.
没好运的话, 它要的是我们
Are there any other artefacts in
the warehouse like this one?
仓库里还有其它类似的物件吗?
I don't know. Maybe. I asked Winslet
to look for anything with the same coding.
我不知道, 也许有. 我跟 Winslet 说过让他找有相同编号的
- Yes, I know. - You obviously know what it was.
- 是的, 我知道  - 你显然知道它是什么
- Is. Yes, I'm afraid I do.  - Well?
- 是的, 恐怕我知道  - 那是?
It's an energy unit.
它是个能量体
It's part of the Nestene Consciousness.
它是 Nestene 意识体的一部分
It has an affinity for plastic.
它对塑料很有亲和力
It's hostile, and God help us
if you have any more artefacts...
它是有敌意的, 如果你还有这样的物件, 老天保佑吧
coded triple A RH 2961.
这种编号为 AAA/RH/2961的
- Greyhound Five to Greyhound One.  - Receiving.
- 灰狗五号呼叫灰狗一号  - 听着呢
There's no radio contact with Greyhound Four.
无线电联系不上灰狗四号了
Winslet's office.
Winslet 的办公室
Check it out and report back.
去检查一下, 然后回报结果
Greyhound Leader.
灰狗队长
Greyhound Leader, come in. Please. Over
灰狗队长, 请回话, 拜托. 挂了
Go ahead, Dan.
继续, Dan
We've found a crate coded triple A RH 2961.
我们找到一个有编号 AAA/RH/2961 的板条箱
- And it's marked Auton.  - Auton.
- 上面标有AUTON  - Auton?
- Is that the only one?  - So far.
- 只有那一个吗?   - 目前是
Has the crate been opened?
板条箱被打开过吗?
- No.  - Any sign of activity?
- 没有  - 有什么活动迹象不?
- No.  - Where are you?
- 没有  - 你们在哪里?
- Storage bay one.  - Keep an eye out for more.
- 储物岛一号  - 盯着点, 看是不是还有
I'm on my way down. Out.
我这就下来, 挂了
You recognised that word. How?
你知道那个词, 怎么回事?
Auton.
Auton.​
I remember Winslet saying it
over the phone just before.
我记得 Winslet 之前在电话里说过
He'd found some crates marked Auton.
他找到了一些标有 Auton 的板条箱
- He told me he didn't find anything.
- I didn't pay much attention at the time,
- 但他跟我说他什么也没找到  - 当时我没怎么留意
but I distinctly remember him saying it.
但我确实记得他说过
- Stay here.  - Wait a minute!
- 待在这里  - 等一下！
What is going on?
到底是什么事?
- What is Auton?
- It's none of your concern.
- Auton 是什么?   - 这不关你的事
Isn't it? I am right in thinking
you blame me for all this, aren't I?
无关吗? 但我理解正确的话, 你责怪我造成这一切, 是吧?
Well, if it's my fault, then I at least think...
好, 如果是我的错, 那我至少觉得...
...I have the right to know what Auton is.
...我有权知道 Auton 是什么
Autons are plastic automata
Auton 是塑料机器人
which can be controlled by the
Nestene Consciousness.
它们会被 Nestene 意识体所控制
They're deadly and virtually indestructible.
它们很致命, 而且基本上坚不可摧
and it seems you've got one
in your storage bay, Doctor Sal.
而且看来你的储物岛里有了一个, Sal 博士
Storage bay one? Let's go.
一号储物岛? 我们走
Doctor Matthews?
Matthews 博士?
Security door.
安全门
- Dan?  - Here.
- Dan?  - 这儿
I suppose you didn't know about this, either.
我估计你对这个也不知情
We're probably looking at
top-grade signal shielding here.
我们在这里看见的可能是最高级的信号屏蔽装置
How do we get it open?
我们怎么打开它?
The question is, do we want to get it open?
问题其实是：我们想要打开它吗?
Retina scan lock.
视网膜扫描锁
It's bound to have your retinaprint on its memory.
它的存储器中一定会有你的视网膜网纹
But what about the entry codes?
密码又怎么弄?
I don't suppose you have the code book for this?
我估计你没有密码本吧?
I didn't even know it was here.
我都不知道有这个
Can you do it?
你能搞定吗
We have to know what we're dealing with.
我们必须知道我们在对付什么
Ramsay, I'd like some of your men here,
just to be on the safe side.
Ramsau, 我希望你的一些人到这里来, 为了安全起见
Sir.
是
This is Greyhound One to Greyhound Six and Seven.
灰狗一号呼叫灰狗六号和七号
Report to Storage bay one immediately.
立即到储物岛一号报到
- Sergeant.  - Defensive positions.
- 长官  - 防御阵型
What are you expecting?
你在期待什么?
You know that danger you were
asking me about earlier?
你记得你之前找我问过的那个危险吧?
Keep them peeled, lads. Keep them peeled.
剥了它们的皮, 小伙子们
Another one.
又有一个
Was the first one just like this?
第一个跟这个一样吗?
Identical. Why?
一模一样. 为什么?
What's the matter?
什么问题?
I'm not sure.
我不确定
There's something different.
有点什么不一样
Not quite what I expected.
跟我原来料想的不太一样
A metamorphosis?
一个变形怪?
The same as before.
跟之前一样
Something's communicating with it.
什么东西正在跟它交流
The other energy unit.
另外一个能量体
We've got to get out of here. Now!
我们得离开这里, 快！
Take this.
拿着这个
All right, Ramsay.
They're not after a conversation.
好啦, Ramsay, 他们不是来找我们聊天的
Open fire!
开火！
We're not going to get out of this alive, are we?
我们不会活着离开这里, 是吗?
I'm open to suggestions.
我愿意接受建议
Why not? Let's try it.
为什么不? 试试吧
- Ramsay?  - Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Ramsay?  - 走！走！走！
No, this way.
不, 这边
No, no, this way.
不对, 不对, 这边
This way, Doctor Dan!
这边, Dan 博士！
Here.
这里
They're jamming us.
他们阻塞了我们的通讯
- Which way is the exit?  - Over this way.
- 哪边是出口?   - 在这边
Poor bastard.
可怜的杂种
He's still alive.
他还活着
They must have copied him. That's what they do.
它们肯定复制了他, 它们会这个
They're using the real Winslet
as a source of information,
它们把真正的 Winslet 用作了信息来源
like a template.
像个模板
Lockwood tell you this?
这个是 Lockwood 告诉你的?
So they could copy anyone.
所以它们能复制任何人
We'd never know the difference.
我们永远不知道区别
Move it.
快走
This is the only way to the exit.
这是出去的唯一途径
They've got us trapped.
它们把我们困住了
And what is this thing?
这个东西又是什么
I don't know, but I've got a good feeling about it.
我不知道, 但我对它有种很好的感觉
Can you get us to your laboratory?
你能带我们到你的实验室吗?
Er, yes. We can cut through here.
呃, 可以, 我们可以从这里切过去
Quick. Barricade the door.
快, 把门堵住
Help me with this.
帮我弄下这个
Hold it, hold it. Couldn't you stop them?
稳住, 稳住. 你能挡住它们吗?
- Not a chance.  - Have they taken the exits?
- 一点机会都没有  - 它们已经拿下出口了么?
- Yes.  - Shit.
- 是的  - 妈的
Lockwood...
Lockwood...​
Lockwood!
Lockwood!​
Just resting my eyes.
休息一下我的眼睛
As your grandmother used to say.
正如你祖母经常说的
How did you know that?
你怎么知道这个?
Your psychoanalysis tests.
从你的心理分析测试
We're all on the great UNIT database.
我们都在 UNIT 的大数据库里
Not even our personalities is safe from trespass.
甚至我们的人格都没法防止被侵入
Has anyone ever told you you're a very...
有没有人告诉过你, 你是一个...
bitter, cynical person, Lockwood?
非常悲天悯人、愤世嫉俗的人, Lockwood?
Don't presume to psychoanalyse me.
别试着对我进行精神分析
That's one degree you don't have, Doctor Sal.
这个学位你可没有, Sal 博士
Only my friends call me that.
只有我的朋友这么叫我
Then I'll refrain.
那我克制一下
What do they want?
它们想要什么?
I suspect they want what's in that tank
in that sealed chamber.
我怀疑它们想要那个密室里面的那个箱子
Which is?
那是...?
Would you take a look at this?
你要看一眼这个吗?
There must be some simple reason
why it isn't working.
它为什么不工作, 肯定有个很简单的原因
And in answer to your question,
作为对你问题的回答
the thing in the tank is a mystery to me;
那个箱子里面的东西对我也是一个谜
As yet.
目前是
Well, it looks like some sort of transmitter but...
嗯, 这个看起来像是某种发射器, 但是...
Okay, it's not as bad as it looks.
好吧, 并不像看起来那么糟糕
How does it look?
看起来怎么样?
I feel like I've had a shave with a cheese grater.
我感觉像是错用了乳酪磨碎器刮了胡子似的
Off the wall humour in the face of excruciating pain?
面对极度的痛苦, 你的幽默感脑洞大开了吗?
We'll make a soldier of you yet, Doctor Dan.
我们会让你成为一个战士的, Dan 博士
Lockwood.
Lockwood.​
Bloody place is crawling with them.
见鬼这个地方到处都是它们
Do you think Lockwood made it?
你觉得 Lockwood 逃脱了吗?
Yeah.
当然
He's indestructible, isn't he?
他是坚不可摧的, 是吧?
What about the others?
其他人呢?
Didn't stand a chance.
一点机会也没有
Oh Christ, I think I'm going into shock.
噢 Christ, 我觉得我要休克了
Oh shit... Ramsay.
噢, 糟了... Ramsay
How the hell are we going to get out of this one?
我们到底要怎么搞定这个问题?
Hello?
哈罗?
Whatever this is, it's got a flat battery,
不管这是什么东西, 它有一个蓄电池
so I'm recharging it, all right?
所以我要给它充电, 行吧?
Oh for God's sake, Lockwood.
噢看在上帝的份上, Lockwood
Doctor!
博士
Doctor Arnold!
Arnold 博士！
Doctor, are you in there?
博士, 你在里面吗?
Doctor Arnold!
Arnold 博士！
Winslet, where the hell have you been?
Winslet, 见鬼你都去哪儿了?
Hiding, Doctor.
躲起来了, 博士
Those dummies. What is going on?
到处是那些人体模型, 发生了什么事?
Everyone out here is dead.
外面的每个人都死了
It's me you want.
你们想要的是我
Kill her and you'll have to kill me.
杀了她你就得杀了我
You're very perceptive, Lockwood.
你的感知力很强, Lockwood
Something different about you.
你有点什么地方不一样
In some ways you're quite like us.
某种程度上你跟我们很像
They've captured Lockwood and that Doctor.
它们抓住了 Lockwood 和那个女博士
Best you don't move.
最好你不要动
Do you know how many times he's saved my life?
你知道他救过我多少次?
We both know how much
pain he goes through for us.
我们都知道他为我们经历多少痛苦
He wouldn't let us down, would he?
他不会让我们倒下的, 对不?
What are you going to do with it
when you've got it?
你拿到它之后打算用它做什么?
That sad remnant in there.
里面那个遗留物
Just a bit of slurry, isn't it?
只是一些浆糊, 是吧?
Left-over scrapings from a body
是一具躯体上的残余部分
you tried to create yourself decades ago.
那是几十年前你试图给自己创造的躯体
I expect it's got a bit of mildew...
我觉得它有点发霉了...
You will open the retina scan door.
你要打开那个视网膜扫描的门
Wel...
这个...
Don't you wish you'd been
a little more pleasant to me?
你没有期望过, 你对我来说变得愉悦一点?
What?
什么?
If I don't help him,
he's probably going to kill you.
如果我不帮他, 他很可能会杀了你
Right? I can't say I really care.
对吧? 我不能说我真的在乎
Of course, then he'll kill me.
当然, 这样他会杀了我
Then what will you do?
那你要怎么办?
Cut my head off and use my retina print?
砍下我的头, 就可以用我的视网膜了?
You still won't have the code.
但你还是没有密码
You are like us.
你跟我们很像
You're linked to something.
你跟什么东西连起来了
What does he mean?
他什么意思?
You should be attending to your battery charger...
你应该去照看你的电池充电器...
Doctor Sal.
Sal 博士
- Come with me.  - We're not leaving him.
- 等我来  - 我们不会撇下他
Yes, you are, if you want to save him.
是的, 你会的, 如果你们想救他的话
Leave them. They're unimportant.
别管他们了, 他们不重要
My God, it works.
上帝啊, 这东西有效
What the hell is that?
这是什么鬼东西?
I've got no idea.
我也没概念
Lockwood...
Lockwood...​
UNIT's creature.
UNIT 的怪物
You cannot resist us.
你们没法抵抗我们
You can fight, but you can't win.
你们可以战斗, 但你们赢不了
Soon.
快了
Soon all the chaos will be over...
很快混沌就会过去...
and you'll be at one...with us
而你会成为我们的一员
Marvellous.
神奇啊
The return of the maverick.
独行侠的回归
Who the...
谁...
what the hell are you?
你是什么鬼?
Think how many people you've killed.
想想你杀了多少人
Why'd you do it?
你为什么这么干?
Because that's what we do.
因为我们就是干这个的
Don't do it.
别做这个
Don't go in there.
别进去
It's too dangerous.
这太危险了
Just keep the door covered.
就让门关上
We'll lock it...
我们会把它锁起来
Get the experts to deal with this thing.
找专家来对付这个东西
Maybe find out some of
its weaknesses for next time.
也许下次能发现它的一些弱点
Next time?
下次?
They've tried before.
他们以前就尝试过
They'll try...
他们还会再次尝试...
My God.
上帝啊
Bloody hell.
见鬼
Where does that lead?
那通到哪里?
Straight to the surface.
直接到地面上
Call for back-up.
呼叫增援吧
Greyhound One.
灰狗一号
Emm, not a bad bit of workmanship,
嗯, 不错的设计
Doctor John Smith.
John Smith 博士
Just returned from the outlying area, sir.
我刚从外面回来, 头儿
How far did you go?
你们走了多远
We estimated a fifty mile radius.
我们评估了大约50英里半径范围
Moorland, mainly.
大都是沼泽地
A few farmhouses, cottages, and suchlike.
一些农舍、茅屋, 诸如此类
Nothing?
没有?
Not a trace.
一点痕迹没有
You've done a good job, Ramsay.
你做得很好, Ramsay
- I can ask for no more.
我不能要求更多了
- Pack up and go.  - Sir.
- 收拾东西走吧  - 是
See you back at base, sir.
在基地见, 头儿
You're a good chap, Ramsay.
你是个好伙计, Ramsay
I used to think your sort
only existed in black and white war films.
我以前认为你这类人只在黑白战争片里面存在
Always salutes when he can't
think of anything to say...
他想不到说什么的时候总是敬礼...
Have you noticed?
你注意到了吗?
How's your face?
你的脸怎么样了?
It's a life-enriching experience.
这次的经历很增长见识
We found particle traces of the Nestene
creature in the external air vents.
我们在外部空气排放口发现了Nestene意识体的粒子痕迹
It's out there somewhere.
它还在外面某个地方
Put it in the bin, Sal.
把它放进包里吧, Sal
Memories can eat away at you, if you let them.
记忆可以吞噬你的, 如果你不防着
Come to escort me to my debriefing?
过来带我去盘问?
- Yes.
- 是的
I also came to thank you.
同时我也是来感谢你?
Thank me for being the idiot
who threw excrement at the fan
感谢我这个傻子, 朝风扇扔分辨?
or whatever it was you said?
或者你是怎么说的来着?
For being insightful..
感谢你富有洞察力
gifted, a bit of a maverick.
有天赋, 有点标新立异
You saved my life, Doctor Sal.
你救了我的命, Sal 博士
I think I'm going to enjoy working with you.
我觉得我会很乐意与你共事
- Working?  - Yes.
- 共事?   - 是得
High-handed of me, I know,/
我是比较专横, 我知道
but I've had you reassigned... to my team.
但我已经安排把你调到了...我的小组
I'm not sure I know what to think about that.
我不知道该怎么看待这事
You're saying I have no choice.
你是说我没有选择
Wretched, isn't it?
很不幸, 是吧?
I don't think I'm ready for your kind of work.
我不觉得我适合你那种工作
Why not?
为什么不?
I caused everything that happened here.
这里发生的事情, 全都是我造成的
- I killed all those people...
- It was out there...
- 是我杀死了那些人...  - 它一直就在那里
waiting to happen.
就等着事情发生
You made a mistake.
你只是犯了一个错误
We all do that.
我们都会犯的
A mistake?
一个错误?
Yes.
是的
We can never know the future...
我们永远不知道未来...
but we mustn't let the past haunt us.
但我们不能让历史跑出来作祟